Ian Cramer

Senior Front End Engineer

330-241-1957

iancramer55@gmail.com

Oleveland, OH

www.therealiancramer.com

Summary

I am a self starter and life-long learner with more than eight years of experience as a front end engineer. I develop public facing single page applications using the most current frameworks and best practices. I am user focused with the ability to make complex data more consumable in a frictionless workflow. I never settle for anything less than my best work and my years in the cyber security industry have pushed me beyond my limits as a UI expert.

Technical Skills

Javascript / ES6 **Typescript** HTML SASS / CSS React **Angular Data Visualization** API **Unit Testing Functional Programming NPM** Performance Optimization Git Accessibility Responsive Design Webpack

Relevant Experience

Senior UI/UX Engineer - FireEye, Inc.

July 2017 - February 2020

- Lead team of international engineers to develop and deliver component library used by engineers company wide and implemented in public facing products in React and Angular
- Managed, published, and versioned component libraries as Node packages
- Fostered collaborative environment between engineering contributors company wide to treat the component library as an "open source" project within the company
- Conducted code reviews for all GitHub pull requests
- Facilitated communication between designers and engineers
- Single handedly deigned and built very successful front end of application for analyzing machine learning models with heavy data visualization
- Guided threat analysis product team to use better Javascript practices to improve performance and user experience

Senior Front End Engineer - Kalibrate

October 2016 - July 2017

- Sole front end engineer in architecting a brand new wholesale fuel pricing application
- Designed and engineered a user interface that dynamically builds itself at run time using user defined metadata retrieved from an API including CRUD operations and navigation elements

Lead Front End Engineer - DecisionDesk

May 2016 - October 2016

- Helped this start-up company in the last few months of its existence to breath life into their product in time for the upcoming college enrollment season
- Lead effort to improve performance and usability while creating a more scalable code base

Education

Bachelor of Arts - Baldwin-Wallace University Studio Art / Computer Science

2006 - 2010